CANDRA EDWARDS

LCSW, LCAS-A

CONTACT

PHONE: (910) 990-1190

EMAIL:

Candra145@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Accomplished mental health professional with vast experience with mental, behavioral, and psychiatric services. I am currently certified as a LCSW and LCAS-A. I am hopeful that my leadership, organization, and willingness to consistently develop as a professional and an individual will position me for success with your organization.

SKILLS

- Cognitive Behavioral Therapy
- Motivational Interviewing
- Art Therapy
- Person-Centeredness
- Grief Counseling

EDUCATION

East Carolina University

May 2013 – May 2016 Master of Social Work, *Cum Laude* (GPA 3.8) Concentration: Substance Abuse Counseling

William Peace University

August 2006- May 2010 B.A.'s Developmental Psychology Minor: Child Development

AWARDS

Trademark Women of Distinction Honors Edition (2019)
Phi Alpha Honor Society (2016)
Chi Zeta Honor Society, 2014
Psi Chi Honors Society (2010)
National Dean's List
Scholar Athlete Award 2007 & 2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

Waynesboro Family Clinic School Based Therapist LCSW, LCAS-A April, 2022-current

- Perform direct patient services as agreed upon with the clinical director as an outpatient therapist (LPC, LCSW, and LCAS)
- Assisting with caseloads of other staff when needed (in their absence)
- Responsible for new client assessments as assigned and assist with crisis walk-in clinic by serving as therapist.
- Responsible for management and scheduling for clients as needed.
- Responsible for conducting Diagnostic Assessment responsibilities in

- addition to completing the initial intakes (90791) to all cilents assigned according to state definitions.
- Responsible for knowing and enforcing the policies of Waynesboro Family Clinic.
- Carry-out clinical responsibilities as an outpatient therapist with fulltime caseload to include initial intakes and subsequent therapy appointment/sessions.
- Use evidence-based theoretical approach in providing services to consumers.
- Utilize weekly supervision in learning and carrying-out clinical responsibilities.

Waynesboro Family Clinic Outpatient Therapist, LCSW, LCAS-A September 14th, 2020-current

- Perform direct patient services as agreed upon with the clinical director as an outpatient therapist (LPC, LCSW, and LCAS)
- Assisting with caseloads of other staff when needed (in their absence)
- Responsible for new client assessments as assigned and assist with crisis walk-in clinic by serving as therapist.
- Responsible for management and scheduling for clients as needed.
- Responsible for conducting Diagnostic Assessment responsibilities in addition to completing the initial intakes (90791) to all cilents assigned according to state definitions.
- Responsible for knowing and enforcing the policies of Waynesboro Family Clinic.
- Carry-out clinical responsibilities as an outpatient therapist with fulltime caseload to include initial intakes and subsequent therapy appointment/sessions.
- Use evidence-based theoretical approach in providing services to consumers.
- Utilize weekly supervision in learning and carrying-out clinical responsibilities.

Waynesboro Family Clinic Community Support Team Lead, LCSW, LCAS-A January 6th, 2020-September 8th, 2022

- Perform direct patient services as agreed upon with the clinical director as an outpatient therapist (LPC, LCSW, and LCAS)
- Assisting with caseloads of other staff when needed (in their absence)
- Handling emergency/urgent/coverage problems on-call when reported by other staff.
- Responsible for new client assessments as assigned and assist with crisis walk-in clinic by serving as therapist.
- Responsible for management and scheduling for clients as needed.
- Responsible for conducting Diagnostic Assessment responsibilities in addition to completing the initial intakes (90791) to all clients assigned according to state definitions.
- Responsible for knowing and enforcing the policies of Waynesboro Family Clinic.
- Carry-out clinical responsibilities as an outpatient therapist with fulltime caseload to include initial intakes and subsequent therapy appointment/sessions.

- Use evidence-based theoretical approach in providing services to consumers.
- Utilize weekly supervision in learning and carrying-out clinical responsibilities.

Nova Behavioral Healthcare ICF/IID Instructor

2013-2020

• Emergency Preparedness (2018-2020)

Developed syllabus and overall course structure and administered all grades for employment requirements.

• NCI+ Instructor (2017-2020)

Developed syllabus and overall course structure and administered all employment requirements.

HIPAA (2014-2017)

Developed syllabus and overall course structure and administered all employment requirements

• Consumer/Client Rights (2014-2020)

Developed syllabus and overall course structure and administered all grades for employment requirements.

• Mental Health Plans (2013-2016)

Developed syllabus and overall course structure and administered all grades for employment requirements.

Nova Behavioral Healthcare ICF/IID Program Program Director

December 2016- January 2020

- Supervises all administrative, nursing, psychiatric, supervisory, and direct care staff.
- Ensures that facility operations are functioning in compliance with and in accordance to, licensure, accreditation, and certification expectations.
- Maintains liaison activities with government and regulatory agencies.
- Oversees an annual budget for facility operations in cooperation with the CEO.
- Navigates complex systems and works to draw out the capacity of individuals to help them fulfill their greatest potential.
- Assists with the transition and implementation an electronic health record system.
- Performs direct patient clinical services as agreed upon by the Clinical Director
- Conducts individual and group counseling sessions with consumers.
- Utilizes an evidence-based theoretical approach to provide therapy services to consumers.

Nova Behavioral Healthcare ICF/IID Program Consumer Affairs Coordinator

June 2014- December 2016

- Provided direct advocacy services to 48 consumers.
- Served as a community representative for the agency and maintained contact with county LME/MCOs, social service agencies, colleges, and other agencies.
- Developed and trained staff on consumer rights, abuse, confidentiality, and other subjects relative to working with consumers.

- Provided and coordinated investigative services in the area of consumer abuse, neglect, and exploitation inquiries and ensure compliance with reporting mechanisms.
- Conducted screenings, intakes, and orientations for admissions.

Nova Behavioral Healthcare Psychiatric Residential Treatment Facility MSW Intern

- Provided individual, group, crisis intervention, conflict mediation, and assessment and referral services to individuals under 21.
- Conducted intakes, led CFT meetings, coordinated with psychiatrist for medication management meetings.
- Participated in admission and discharge meetings providing information for continuity of care.

Nova Behavioral Healthcare ICF/IID Program QP/IID

October 2010- June 2014

- Developed, implemented, and monitored habilitation plans and behavior support plans.
- Evaluated each assigned group home for compliance and identified deficiencies.
- Developed corrective action for all programmatic/operational deficiencies with internal and external audits.
- Conducted staff personnel actions as warranted; including performance appraisals, disciplinary action, positive reinforcement, interviewing, hiring and termination recommendations.
- Coordinated treatment planning with specific experience developing crisis plans.

William Peace University Resident Assistant

August 2009- May 2010

- Assisted freshmen students with the adjustment to the academic, financial, social, and emotional stressors of college life.
- Conducted monthly meetings to promote resident cohesiveness.
- Conducted mediations with students and made referrals for issues beyond the scope of practice.
- Served as a positive role model to all students and encouraged all to seeks opportunities to become leaders.

Cherry Hospital (North Carolina State Government Internship Program) Teen Hope Coordinator

May 2009- August 2009

- Conducted interviews for all volunteers
- Developed orientation structure
- Performed performance evaluations for each volunteer to ensure quality service.
- Coordinated with Volunteer Services to organize fundraising projects

LICENSURES & CERTIFICATIONS

 LCSW (August 10th, 2022 thru August 10th, 2024) C015225

LCAS-A